So, let us welcome to the another video and in this video, we are going to discuss one
of the important security mechanism that was commonly used in Windows operating system.
Its name does as a anti-malware scan interface, AMSI, so many of them here about the
aim of AMSI, so AMSI is basically anti-malware scan interface, so this was a security
mechanism that was introduced by Windows operating system and it was this, it was mostly
used by the PowerShell, command prompt and many more, to detect a malicious script, okay.
So whenever, for example, whenever you try to load any malicious script from the PowerShell.exe,
so the AMSI will be the first one, it will detect that PowerShell script, malicious
PowerShell script and it will terminate that process, okay.
So this is the main features of AMSI, so this is one of the very powerful different
mechanism that was introduced by Windows, okay.
So this different mechanism will mainly focus on file as malware, so the file as malware
will be like, there is no files.ts or not that file, the file as malware will be like
the base 64 encoder command, it will directly run into the PowerShell.exe and it will inject
something into the memory, okay.
That was the, that was the, we are calling that as a file as malware, okay.
So let's, let's discuss some of the topic like someone will be thinking like, I have a
bit different array, why I need AMSI to my protection, okay.
So let's think about your bit different antivirus only have the static signatures, hashes,
okay.
The malicious hash files, so it will only scan, scan the, scan your file by using the signature
hash files, right.
So it will detect only the malicious hash, which it will be matched into our files, right.
So for example, if you are downloading mimicats.exe file, if the mimicat.exe hash was
present in the bit different signature, it will detect that, it will detect the hash,
let me get file, right.
So let's come to the example of file as malware, if you are loading any, any script, which
was file, file us into directly into the PowerShell.exe, so that time your AV engine does
not have an idea to how to detect that and what is it, right.
So in that time the AMSI or the anti-malware scan interface will come to play, okay.
So let's, I will explain that in practical, so let's, anyone have a doubt what is a file
as malware, so let I will give some example of what is a file as malware, okay.
So let, I will open a PowerShell in the administrator mode and I'm giving a parameter called
a function and I'm giving the variable, you know, let I will give my name and I will type
the right host, I will later explain what it will, what it will do, okay.
So now my, okay, so, give me some time, let's load this.
Okay, it's saying the missing name after the argument, okay, it was detected, let try to
the PowerShell.exe, so it has to be loaded, let I will open the PowerShell, the administrator
mode, let's, let's try now, you can see TIO and, okay, now we get green, right.
So now my function parameter was there, that I will give, in work, H, A, Y, and I'm writing
a script, write host and bypass, A, B, let I will close this script.
So now if I give the in work, H, A, Y, so it loaded, what I return inside the function,
right, write host function, right.
So this is the file as malware, so you can load your malicious script, malicious basically
4 or obfuscated script inside the write host or other function and you can directly load
that into the memory, okay, this is the very simple example, what is file as malware, so
you can script, you can use the PowerShell script and you can develop your own malicious
script and you can load into the target machine, so it will directly load, the script will
directly load into the memory and it was not detected by most of the A, B engines as well
as the EDR, okay, for some time your EDR will also fail to detect this kind of malicious
script that was directly injected from the PowerShell, okay, so let's talk something with
the AMSI by pass, so how can I will do the AMSI by pass, okay, so let's see what happening
in the PowerShell first, let I will open my process explorer, so I already explained the
AMSI engine will mostly concentrate on PowerShell.exe to detect a file as malware, okay,
so let I will load the PowerShell into my process explorer and I will see what actually
happening in the PowerShell, so how my AMSI engine will know, how my Windows Defender
engine will know the script was malicious, how it will know, okay, let's load this, let's
wait for the dealers getting loaded, let's open up PowerShell, another PowerShell, let's
see, okay, so now you can see the PowerShell.exe and most of the dealers get loaded, so
you can see two dealers that was used for a different mechanism, so here you can see the
different, uh, bit different security, right, so why my bit different dealer was inside my
PowerShell.exe, let's think about it, okay, so for example, if your antivirus need to monitor
the PowerShell.exe, if your antivirus need to monitor the behavior of the PowerShell.exe,
your antivirus need to inject a code into the PowerShell.exe, okay, your antivirus need
to inject a code or a dealer into your PowerShell.exe to monitor what happening inside the
PowerShell.exe, if it did not load a dealer dealer or a code into the PowerShell.exe,
your antivirus do not know what happening inside the PowerShell.exe, okay, so let's take
a real example, so in your opposite home, let's take an example of opposite home, so there
is a big fight going inside your opposite home, okay, so you are waiting outside the home,
you don't know what happening inside the, what happening inside that home, right, so if you go
into the system, go into that home, you can understand what was the actual problem, okay,
that there was an example here, okay, your antivirus or Windows Defender need to monitor
the PowerShell.exe, it need to inject a code or a dealer file into your PowerShell and it
will monitor what happening inside the PowerShell.exe, okay, so if it monitor, so your
for example, if the bit different or dealer monitors any suspicious activity that was
running inside the PowerShell, it will terminate that process, okay, this is how your EDR,
AV engines and other defense mechanism will work whenever a threat occurred, okay, so
let's take an example of a process injection, so you are injecting some code into your target
process, your target process behavior has been changed, right, so your target process
will act like a malware, it will give command and control to the threat attack, okay,
in that time your AMSI or your defense mechanism, such as AV, it will detect suspicious
behavior and it will terminate the process, okay, so this is the actual explanation of
how your EDR and AV engines will work, so here you can see the AMSI.dll was loaded
inside the PowerShell.exe, so my AMSI.dll will monitor the PowerShell.exe whatever happens,
whatever malicious activity happens, it will terminate that process, okay, so this is the actual
behavior of the defense mechanisms like Windows Defender and Antiverse Engine, okay, so
let's load some malicious script into the PowerShell, let I will load directly load an
invoke multicat, okay, invoke MMI, sorry, so if I give, so you can now see suspicious activity
where blocked, so my Antiverse system is also active, as well as my AMSI is also
active, both are combined with each other and it was detecting it as a threat, right,
so whenever I tried to load the invoke MMI cat's module inside the PowerShell, my command
get detected as a malware and it was blocked by your Antiverse software, so in this scenario
my Windows Defender, as well as my bit differenter, both are collaborating with each
other and it was detecting a threat, right, so this is the common example of how your
Antiverse software or your AMSI was detecting the malicious script, okay, so how I will
bypass this, did you think about what I need to do whenever I come to the defense
activation mechanism, how I will bypass this script, okay, so let's go to some more example,
when you inject, when you pass any, when you pass the any base 64 or obfuscated script
inside the PowerShell, your PowerShell will try, your defense mechanism will tries to de-uff
a gate or decode that PowerShell script and it will search for the common string that
was used by the malware and it will detect that as a malicious, okay, so we know if I
passed the invoke MMI cat that was absolutely a malicious thing, your defense mechanism
captured the string, invoke MMI cat string and detect some malicious content, so see detection
does a malicious content, so this is the malicious content, right, so how we can bypass,
let's, okay, many of them know what is MMI cat, so MMI cat is one of the post exploitation
module, like the meta-spitable framework, let's think about the meta-spitable framework,
so we can, we can use the MMI cat for many type of attacks like credential access, dumping
hashes, Kerbro slated attacks, pasta hash attacks, active directory based attacks, and
we, we can do a lot of things with MMI cat, we will see that in our team operations, so
let's come to our discussion, so how, I, how I will bypass this, okay, let I will do one
thing, okay, my, I know my, a, b engine and different, different, Windows Defender engine
will detect, this is some malicious content, let I will split that content, okay, let I will
go to, let I will do one thing, I n, plus, I will split that content, I will give, okay,
b or, plus, k e, plus, dash, plus, m, i, plus.
m, i, plus, k, a, plus, t, z, okay, so now I split out all the things, right, in
b, o, k, a, plus, dash, and m, i, m, i, m, k, a, t, z, now I will load, so let's see
what will happen, so see, my script get executed, right, my in-mode MMI cat script get executed,
this is how you need to bypass the, a, m, i engine using the, using the splitting strings
mechanism, okay, you can split the strings and you can execute that, okay, I will give
some other example to bypass the different Windows Defender AMSA engine, so you can split
your code and you can use the basics for, with your basics for encoder, as well as you
can obfuscate the string, okay, obfuscate, split the string, do the basics for encoding
and obfuscate that, obfuscate that code, okay, so now inject that code inside your PowerShell
I am damn sure your PowerShell or AMSA engine will not detect that script, okay, so in our
example I just, I did not do any encoding or any encryption or any obfuscation, I just
split out the string, I can bypass my AV engine as well as my AMSA engine, right, so this
is the way you, you can think about when you are coming to bypassing the AMSA and the
malware scanning interface or the antivirus engines, okay, so I will use other examples also,
but I will hardly prefer, you can, you can use the hot code strings like, you can encrypt
encoder do that mechanism to bypass the engines, but we have other mechanism also, you
can terminate the Windows Defender or you can go for some third party tools like, here
you can see the invoke AMSA bypass.ps1, you can directly load this PowerShell script into
the, into the PowerShell console and your PowerShell, it will do some memory patching and
it will do some, it will load a load, a memory buffer and mainly it will load, it will pass
the AMSA, okay, so bypassing the AMSA, you can easily bypass the AMSA, but I would not
prefer this kind of things, but because your EDRs are very easy, AV engine already have
this hash inside the static signature, so I will hardly prefer, you can, you can go for,
you can go for a obfuscation encoding encryption and splitting the strings, okay, so this
method I will give you to follow whenever you come to the AV, AV or AMSA bypass, okay,
so I hope you, you will understand all about the AMSA engine, how it was working, what
was the difference, a difference mechanism it was follows and how to evade that difference
mechanism to bypass the, bypass the AV engine as well as the AMSA to inject your
malicious script, so hope you understand and you have a clear understand about this video
and we will see you in the next video, bye bye, thank you.